Let's go through the wire frames for the settings UI.
Within the detail activity in the overflow menu, there's a settings menu item.
When you tap on the setting's menu item, it opens up the settings activity.
If you tap of location, it pops up a dialog, where you can enter in your
postal code. Feel free to use your preferred method for inputting location,
such as city name. Just verify that the data coming back from the server is for
the location you expect. Note that there's no validation on this string input.
If you're trying to make this app a production app, you would want some kind of
air handling here. If you tap on pick your units, it opens up a dialogue
where you can choose to display temperature within the app as wither metric or
imperial units. This is basically just Celsius or Fahrenheit, and
that is what this settings activity does. Remember that you don't want to make
everything a setting. If you're discussing a feature with a teammate and you
can't decide on something, don't compromise by just making it a user setting.
There are instances where making a difficult product decision now will be better
for the user, because then they won't have the burden of having to decide what
the value of the setting should be. And remember, there's always an opportunity
in an app update to add the setting later. If you add it to begin with, it's
infinitely harder to take away the setting because some users might get angry
with you. If you're having trouble deciding if something should be a setting or
not, you can check out the setting section in the Android design guide,
which is linked below. It contains a workflow diagram that could help you.
Very few roads often lead to making something a setting.